我是杰森.西弗，是个心理医生
Hi, I'm Jason Seaver. I'm a psychiatrist.
过去15年里 我致力于解决患者的问题
I've spent the last 15 years helping people with their problems.
我是麦姬.西弗
And I'm Maggie Seaver.
过去15年里，我一直围着孩子们转
I've spent the last 15 years helping our kids with problems...
解决那些杰森也束手无策的问题
even Jason wouldn't believe.
现在麦姬已重操旧业 在一家当地报社做记者
Now, Maggie has gone back to work as a reporter for the local newspaper.
杰森把他的诊所搬到了家里 这样就可以陪着孩子们了
Jason has moved his practice into the house so he can be there for the kids.
-他们是可爱的孩子 -大多时候都是
- They're great kids. - Most of the time.
-但是有时… -反正我们很爱他们
- And the rest of the time? - We love them anyway.
是的
Yeah.
鬼才相信
Unbelievable.
(English Subtitle) Growing.Pains.S01E03 -= Jealousy =- Subripped by zerox
可以了，谁要吃炒鸡蛋？
Here we go. How many for scrambled eggs?
好吧，谁要昨晚的牛肝？
Okay, how many for last nights liver?
谁要吃炒鸡蛋？
Now how many for scrambled eggs?
爸爸，我的科学实验遇到问题了
Dad, I'm having some trouble with my science project.
-要我帮忙吗？ -我想知道科学实验是什么
- You need some help with it? - I need to know what it is.
-那么，你在研究些什么东西呢？ -科学知识呗
- Well, what are you studying in science? - Science stuff.
很好，这是个良好开端
Okay. That's a good start.
凯罗 你小学3年级时的科学实验是什么？
Carol, what did you do for your third-grade science project?
我制造了一种 单二氯化物和聚二氯化物的混合物
Well, I constructed a compound of monodichlorides and polydichlorides...
这种混合物可以承受极度高温和高压
that we're capable of withstanding excessive heat and mechanical stress.
麦克呢？
Mike?
我测试超级球弹得有多高
I ran tests to see how high a Super Ball would bounce.
至少我们知道如何定义科学的界限了
Well, at least we've now defined the boundaries of science.
-大家早啊 -妈妈早
- Morning, everybody. - Hi, Mom.
-你今天真漂亮 -谢谢
- Hi, you look nice. - Thanks.
的确是很漂亮
Wow. You sure do.
-吃炒鸡蛋吗？ -没时间了
- You want some eggs? - No time.
我8点半还有个 关于有毒废料的采访
I've got this 8:30 interview on this toxic waste story.
你知道吗？ 现在整个长岛都是这种有毒废料
Do you realize that they are just dumping this stuff all over Long Island?
这些毒素很可能就在我们的水和食物里
It may very well be in our water, even our food.
甚至在鸡蛋里
Even in our eggs.
我要迟到了，再见
I'm gonna be late. Bye, everybody.
-再见 -再见，午饭时候见
- Bye, hon. - Bye-bye. See you at lunch.
午饭？
Lunch?
你说过回来一起吃午饭的
Yeah, you're gonna meet me back here for lunch.
简森，对不起，我完全忘了
Oh, Jason, I'm sorry. I completely forgot.
没关系
No problem.
那我们中午见了？
So, well see you about noon?
问题是我中午 也许抽不出时间回家
Well, the problem is I don't think I'll have time to come home.
爸爸，你的手艺太差 还是带她出去吃吧
It's your cooking, Dad. Take her out.
好主意
Good idea.
不如我到你报社去，和你到外面去吃吧
Look, why don't I just come by there and I'll take you out for lunch.
我不知道什么时候才有空
I'm not sure what time I'll be free.
简森，我不想你在那里干等着
Jason, I don't want you to have to wait around.
没关系，我倒很有兴致
That's no problem. It'll be fun for me.
我还没见过你上班时的样子呢
I haven't seen you in action at your office.
我…
Well, l....
你就答应吧，妈妈 他正求你和他约会呢
Mom, come on. The guys begging for a date.
他很少有这么主动的
I don't know how much more of this I can watch.
-好，好.. -好吧，到时见
- Okay, okay, okay. - All right. See you there.
-再见 -再见
- See you later. - Bye-bye.
-再见 -太好了!
- Bye. - Yes!
格维克太太，水库里倾倒废物的事.
No, Mrs. Curwick, you see, we suspect that Easttown is giving you...
我们怀疑垃圾厂.
and your neighbors a lot of false information...
欺骗了你和你的邻居
about what's been dumped in that reservoir.
对
Right.
我就是这个意思
See, that's just what I mean.
世上根本没有“含沙的”水
You see, there's no such thing as "chunky-style" water.
备案？好的
For the record? Good.
请稍等
Just one minute, okay?
周一如何？
How about Monday?
-可以打个电话吗？ -可以，在那边
- Mind if I make a call? - Sure, right over there.
打电话而已，不是发射导弹啊
I wanna place a call, not launch an MX missile.
喂，我是西弗医生 请问安德森先生在吗？
Hello, this is Dr. Seaver. Mr. Anderson in, please?
不，我准是打错了.
No, I'm sorry, I must've misdialed then, I was....
不，我不是要登广告
No, I don't wish to place a classified ad.
我知道价钱很公道
No, I'm sure that's a very good per-word price...
我只是想打个外线电话而已
but no, I'm trying to get an outside line, here.
我没有要跟谁一起登广告
No, I'm not going to be placing the ad with anyone else.
我要找一个病人
I'm trying to reach a patient.
轻度精神分裂，偶尔的自大狂.
Mildly schizophrenic, delusions of grandeur, occasional....
就跟踪这件事，我们支持你
Let's go with this one. Yes, I'll be right with you, Mrs. Curwick.
还有这个
And this one.
麦姬
Maggie.
刚才打到莫斯科了
I think I just leveled Moscow.
-我可以走了 -去哪里吃饭？
- Okay, I'm all set here. - So, where do you want to eat?
-小麦，吃饭去 -小麦？
- Hey, Mags, wanna grab some lunch? - "Mags"?
弗瑞德，这是我丈夫杰森.西弗
Fred, I want you to meet my husband, Jason Seaver.
天哪!我竟然没看到你
Jeez, I didn't even see you down there.
杰森，这是弗瑞德
Jason, this is Fred Mathis.
我和他合作报导废料倾倒的事
Fred's the one I'm working with on the toxic waste story.
不必起来
No, don't get up.
-幸会 -幸会
- Hey, it's really nice to meet you. - Well, it's nice to meet you.
小麦经常说起你
Mags has told me a lot about you.
你怎么不告诉我弗瑞德的事？
Well, why didn't you tell me about Fred?
可怜的小麦整天对着我.
Well, poor Mags is stuck with me all day.
回到家当然不想提起我了
I'm sure the last thing she wants to do when she gets home is talk about me.
才不是
That's not true.
昨天不是说过吗？
I told you about Fred just yesterday.
不记得了？
Don't you remember?
是啊
Yeah.
因为你在我印象中.
I think I just pictured you differently.
是秃顶的，胖一点
Balder, fatter.
记者的公众形象就是这样
Well, that's the public for you. They think we all look like Lou Grant.
幸好小麦不是如此
Thank God Mags doesn't, huh, Jason?
我要和杰森去吃饭
Jason and I we're just about to grab a bite.
那不打扰了
Well, I wont keep you. Excuse me.
2点钟会议前.
Mags, I will need to see you for a couple of minutes...
我要跟你谈谈
before that meeting at 2:00.
现在已经1点半了
And it's 1 :30 now.
弗瑞德，一起吃饭吧
Well, look, Fred, why don't you just join us for lunch?
-我不想打扰你们 -我坚持
- I don't want to impose. - No, I insist.
-你们两个有公事 -杰森，你真的太好了
- You two have work to do together. - That's very nice of you, Jason.
垃圾厂的两个暴徒.
Mags, I didn't tell you, two of these goons tried to muscle me...
还想揍我呢
when I was out at that Easttown dump.
他们个子一定很高大
Must have been some big goons.
凯罗，为什么不帮我写论文？
Come on, Carol, why cant you just write this essay for me?
因为这是你的作业
Because it's your assignment.
你写得更好
Yeah, but you'd do a better job.
你若坚持下去，受伤害的是这篇论文
I mean, look, you're standing on principle and the result is that the essay suffers.
你没有良心责备？
Now, do you really want that on your conscience?
我宁受良心责备
That's the private hell I choose to live within.
麦姬
Maggie?
好像是关车门的声音
I thought I heard a car door slam.
我也跟邻居说过好多遍.
No, you know, Dad, no matter how many times I ask the neighbors...
让他们从车窗爬下来
to please climb out through their windows...
但他们坚持开车门
they insist on using those doors.
麦克，多嘴!
Don't be a wise guy, Mike.
-凯罗，表几点了？
-10：03 - Carol, what time does your watch say? - 10:03.
-你的表坏了？ -没有，10：02
- Why? Is yours broken? - No, it says 10:02.
还以为表停了
I just thought it might have stopped.
它显然停过，接着你上发条逼它再走
Apparently, it did, Dad. But it sounds like you've nipped it in the bud.
麦姬？弗瑞德
Maggie? Fred.
没有，我会让她马上回电
Hi. Yeah, no, Ill have her call you right away.
好吧，你也是
Okay. You, too.
再见
Yeah, bye.
弗瑞德？
Fred?
对，跟你妈妈一起报道有毒废料的人
Yeah, Fred's the guy your mother's working on that toxic waste story with.
他看上去不错，很不错.
He seems like a nice guy. Very nice.
非常很不错
Darn nice.
你们别幼稚了好吗？
Will you guys act your age?
-大家好 -妈妈
- Hi, everybody. - Hey, Mom.
麦姬，我没听见你关车门
Maggie! I didn't even hear your car door slam.
下次我会用力点
Well, Ill try and do it louder next time.
今天大家怎样？做些什么了？
Well, guys, how's it going? What did you do today?
-我今天.. -小孩子没什么事做
- Well, I went-- - Nothing. They're children.
他们的生活枯燥乏味
They have boring, uneventful lives.
你呢？谈谈你的报道吧
How was your day? Tell us about that story.
杰森，真抱歉，午餐成了会议
Jason, I'm sorry our lunch got turned into a work session.
别逗了，我觉得还好
No, are you kidding? That was great for me.
我对淤泥的认识居然如此贫乏
It was shocking for me to discover how little I knew about sludge.
-垃圾厂怎样了？ -亲爱的，我累了
- What about the Easttown dump? - Honey, I am really bushed.
暂时不想提那些事
I'd rather not even think about that stuff for a while.
-可以吗？ -好吧
- Okay? - Okay. Sure.
爸爸，你忘了弗瑞德刚打过来
Hey, Dad, don't forget to tell her Fred just called.
弗瑞德？太好了，我正要跟他谈谈
Fred called? Oh, good. I need to talk to him.
明天得完成报道.
We're gonna break this story tomorrow...
即使今晚要通宵
if it means working till midnight.
恨不得马上揪住那群流氓
I just cant wait to nail those creeps.
弗瑞德，嗨
Fred? Hi.
开玩笑!
you're kidding.
大家觉得我第一次烤的烙饼怎样？
So how did everyone enjoy my first foray into the wonderful world of pancakes?
已经超越煮牛肝的成就
Well, it beat the heck out of your foray into the wonderful world of liver.
爸爸，三年级时你做过什么科学课题
Dad, did they have science projects when you we're in third grade?
本，爸爸三年级时 连科学课都没有
Ben, when Dad was in the third grade, they didn't have science.
老实说，爸爸那时候 连三年级都没有
In fact, when Dad was in the third grade, they didn't have the third grade.
麦克，人说幽默感是儿童成长的最后阶段
Mike, they say the sense of humor is the final stage of child development.
你快要进入那个阶段了
You ought to feel it coming on any time now.
我三年级时做了个很好的课题
Yes, Ben. I did a wonderful project in third grade.
-我让面包发霉 -故意的？
- I grew mold on bread. - On purpose?
我认为霉菌在白面包上.
Yes, I determined that mold would grow faster on white bread...
比黑面包长得快
than on pumpernickel.
这样我应该换个方向了
I think I should strike out in new directions.
你应该找自己感兴趣的课题
Well, what you really have to do is find something that interests you.
这样才能让你学到更多
And that way the project will teach you the most.
-车来了，再见 -甜心，祝你今天愉快
- Rides here. Bye, Mom. - Bye, sweetie. Have a good day.
妈妈，你今天真漂亮
Nice talking to you, Mom. You look great again.
谢谢，你也是
Thanks. Looking good yourself.
是啊，我戒酒了
Well, yeah. You know, been cutting down on the beer.
-我也是 -祝你今日愉快
- Me, too. - You, too. Have a good day.
我也走了
I'm out of here, too.
我和弗瑞德今晚可能加班
Remember, Fred and I will probably be working late again tonight.
你看什么时候能回来？
Okay, so what time you think you'll be home?
-难说.. -估计
- Well, it's hard to say-- - Estimate.
应该是9点到11点之间
I don't know between 9:00 and 11 :00, I'd say.
这叫估计？ 估计应该是9：05至9：06
You call that an estimate? An estimate is 9:05, 9:06.
好吧，10：00到10：15
Okay. Lets say between 10:00 and 10:15.
10：00还是10：15？
Well, which one? 10:00 or 10:15?
不知道，差15分钟而已
I don't know, Jason. It's only 15 minutes.
“15分钟而已”？
"It's only 15 minutes"?
15分钟而已可以发生很多事情
Maggie, a lot can happen in 15 minutes.
泰坦尼克号15分钟内沉没了
The Titanic sunk in 15 minutes.
查尔斯.海斯顿15分钟内得到了
Charlton Heston picked up ten commandments in 15 minutes.
我们的第一个孩子就发生在15分钟内 最多15分钟!
Our first child was conceived in 15 minutes. Tops!
杰森，你吃醋了？
Jason, are you jealous?
吃什么醋？
Jealous? Of what?
妒忌我和弗瑞德，我们加班
Of me and Fred. You know, working late.
这想法太可笑了
Of you and.... That is a comical thought.
-杰森，你吃醋了 -我没有
- Jason, you are jealous. - No, I'm not.
-是的 -我没有吃醋
- Come on. Yes, you are. - No, I'm not jealous, Maggie.
我是个心理医生.
I'm a psychiatrist. I'm also a man with a heightened degree...
具备高度的自我意识.
of self-awareness, and for that reason I can admit...
我感到失落，因为你和你的同事.
to a certain sense of loss over the fact that you now share things...
能在晚上10：00或者11：00交流
with a professional colleague until 10:00 or 11 :00 at night.
而我们之间不能交流
Things you and I are unable to share.
但我得加一句，若你的同事是女的.
But I hasten to add, I would feel exactly the same way...
我也会有同样的感觉
if your colleague we're a woman.
也许你说得对
Well, you're probably right.
说什么“也许”!
Well, theres no "probably" about it, Maggie!
我的职业是分析人们的动机
Analyzing peoples motivations is what I do for a living.
而不是出于两性之间的忌妒
I am not sexually jealous.
我对你的信任排除了忌妒的可能性
I have far too much faith in you to ever be sexually jealous.
希望你也能同样地信任我
And I would appreciate it if you had the same faith in me.
对不起，杰森，我只是说笑
I'm sorry, Jason. I was just kidding.
原谅我吗？
Forgive me?
好吧
Well, okay.
很好，回头见
Okay? Good, Ill see you later.
那你什么时候回来？
So, what time you think you'll be home?
-麦克，别吵 -什么？我没有
- Mike, cut it out! - What? I wasn't doing anything.
麦克，别打扰妹妹了
Mike, will you stop bothering your sister?
-爸爸，“选举”的同义词是？ -“投票”
- Dad, what's another word for "election? " - Plebiscite.
我没问你，我问爸爸
I didn't ask you. I asked Dad.
有什么不同？
What's the difference?
不同点在于不要你告诉我
The difference is I don't want to know from you.
对不起
Sorry.
该怎么拼？
How do you spell it?
-为什么要告诉你怎么拼？ -因为我问你了
- Why should I tell you how to spell it? - Because I asked you.
你不是不要我告诉你吗？
I thought you didn't want to know things from me.
你是个律师吗？
What are you? A lawyer?
我是帮你锻炼脑子
I mean, I'm trying to do you a favor here by finding a use for your brain...
你却以怨报德
and out of nowhere, you turn on me like a wild dog.
够了!
Cut it out!
女性对象在第三下后手腕被抓住
Female subject grabs wrist after third click.
再来我就宰了你
You do that again and Ill kill you.
男性对象在第一下后有生命危险
Male subject threatens death after first click.
-本，你在干什么？ -我的科学课题
- Ben, what are you doing? - It's my science project.
我在测试不同的人在不同的刺激下.
I'm testing to see how long it takes certain people...
会做出什么反应
to respond to certain stimuli.
这个课题不好，中止测试
Well, that's not a good science project, so stop it.
是你让我找有兴趣的课题
But you told me to do something that interests me.
我对凯罗和麦克的兴趣超过霉菌
Mike and Carol interest me more than mold.
你的话很感动，但别说了
That's a touching sentiment, Ben. Now cut it out.
他是怎么了？
What's with him?
他不喜欢你，从来如此
He doesn't like you. He never has.
爸爸，妈妈什么时候回来？
Hey, Dad, when's Mom coming home?
难道我长得像预言家？
Do I look like Jeane Dixon, Mike?
你妈妈是个职业女性.
Your mother's a working adult and when she's finished working...
下班后自然回家
shell come home.
早点回来就好了，她能想到好的课题
I wish she'd get here, "cause she thinks of great science projects.
-是吗？ -去年她让我研究蝌蚪
- She does? - Last year she picked tadpoles.
这就对了
Well, that's it, then.
今年不能再做了，学校有记录
I cant do tadpoles, again. They keep these things on file.
不，我是说你妈妈
No, I mean your mother.
我们该去问妈妈
We should be asking your mother what to do.
我现在就去报馆问她
In fact, I think Ill go down to that newspaper office right now and ask her.
干嘛不打个电话
Dad, why don't you just call her?
显然你没见过她们的电话
Obviously you haven't seen the phones they have down there.
走一趟比电话省事多了
Believe me, it's be a lot simpler this way.
-这会打扰她的 -绝对不会
- Wont that be bothering her, Dad? - Absolutely not.
你妈妈喜欢决定这种事情
No, no. Your mother wants to be involved in these decisions.
再说，这么晚了，我怎么忍心让她.
Besides, I don't like the idea of her being down at the office...
一个人待在办公室？
this late at night, all by herself.
她不是一个人，还有弗瑞德
She's not all by herself. Fred's with her.
尽管如此
Even so.
弗瑞德，是谁？
Fred, who's that?
不知道，看门人？
I don't know. The janitor?
清洁工怎么会用鼻子擦玻璃？
No one who cleans for a living would press his nose against glass.
也许是垃圾厂的流氓
Maybe it's one of those goons from the Easttown dump site.
我来报警
No, Ill call the police.
-杰森! -杰森？
- Jason! - Jason?
-没事吧？ -亲爱的
- Are you all right? - Honey.
-对不起，不知道是你 -没关系，我没事
- I'm sorry, I didn't know it was you. - No, no, I'm fine.
进来坐下
Come in here and sit down.
幸亏有鼻子挡着，没砸到脸
Fortunately, my nose stopped the door before it could hit my face.
杰森，来这干嘛？
Jason, what are you doing here?
来这干嘛？
What am I doing here?
是本的事
It's about Ben.
-什么事？要紧吗？ -当然要紧
- Jason, what is it? Is it serious? - Well, of course it's serious.
不然我也不会来这
I wouldn't come down here if it wasn't serious, would l?
麦姬，我真的不知道如何处理好了
I don't know what to do with the boy, Maggie.
他对霉菌缺乏热情
He's got a bad attitude about mold.
他还说再次研究蝌蚪是不道德的
And it's just not ethical for him to do tadpoles again.
失陪了，这好像是私事
Excuse me. This sounds personal.
你是来监视我的吧？
You came down here to check up on me, didn't you?
太有意思了
Oh, well, that's great. That's just great.
我来这里是讨论小儿子的前途
I come down to discuss the welfare of our youngest son.
他是我们的孩子 别歪曲理解我的好意
Our baby, if you will, and you twist it into something sordid.
我要是正常点，甚至会就此愤愤离去
I have a good mind I should just turn around and walk out of here right now.
真是不敢相信.
I don't believe this. I mean, you thought....
你真的以为我和弗瑞德在偷情？
You actually thought there was something going on between me and Fred?
我不屑回答这个问题
I cant even dignify that with a response.
你更喜欢他对不对？
You like him better than me, don't you?
杰森
Jason.
行了，麦姬，我可不是白痴
Come on, Maggie, admit it, I'm not a complete idiot.
-麦姬，吃早饭吗？ -没时间
- "Maggie, do you want some eggs? " - "No time."
麦姬，中午一起吃饭吗？
Well, "Maggie, how about if we meet for lunch?
我完全忘记了
"Oh, I completely forgot."
麦姬，今天怎样了？
Well, "Maggie, how was your day today?
我不想谈，弗瑞德打来了？
"l don't want to talk about it. Fred called?
我有时间跟他聊!
"Oh, I have time to talk to him! "
-杰森 -别敷衍我
- Jason. - Don't "Jason" me, Maggie.
我发现你最近开始打扮
I've also been watching the way you're dressing lately.
现在我懂了
And now I understand it.
因为他会看见你，你在他眼中.
it's because when he looks at you, he looks at you as if you were....
就像个女人!
As if you we're a woman!
我自己也搞不清楚呢
Yeah, you know, at first I couldn't figure that out.
现在我明白了，我是个女人
And then it dawned on me. I am a woman.
你承认了!
So, you admit it.
你现在挺得意了吧？
you're into this, Maggie. You enjoy it.
对，很得意
Yeah, I enjoy it.
别人对我有兴趣，我感觉良好
People find me interesting and that makes me feel good.
这有什么不对？
What's wrong with that?
不对的是你让丈夫备受煎熬
What's wrong with it is, you're putting your husband through a living hell.
麦姬，我从来没有这样对你
And, Maggie, I would never do that to you.
什么意思？
What do you mean....
意思是15年来我洗衣做饭.
Means I spent 15 years in sweatpants cleaning toilets...
你却穿着时髦的亲衫在办公室.
while you went down to your office in your sexy psychiatrists sweater...
还穿着时髦的外套.
and your sexy psychiatrists jacket--
我的外套不是时髦，是羊毛
My jackets aren't sexy, Maggie, they're tweed.
女人最喜欢羊毛的了
Women die for tweed and you know it.
这个我控制不了
I have no control over that.
多少个夜晚我等你下班.
And how many nights did I spend watching your broccoli go limp...
等到花椰菜都谢了
while I waited for you to come home?
堵车嘛
I was fighting traffic, Maggie.
兴漂亮的同事一起挤在车上
Yeah, with that brilliant young psychiatrist in your car pool.
-罗森医生？ -珍妮.罗森医生
- Dr. Rosenblum? - Dr. Jennifer Rosenblum.
而且是老跟你坐在前座的珍妮医生
Who, as I noticed, always managed to ride in the front seat next to you.
因为她的腿很长
Maggie, she had very long legs.
那我就放心了
Well, that's a relief.
那么你们双双飞到芝加哥参加会议.
I hope legroom wasn't a problem when the two of you...
她的长腿没有引发问题吧？
jetted off to Chicago for that psychiatric convention.
我们在合作写论文
We we're writing a paper together.
我记得了
Yes, I remember it.
Human Sexual Inhibitions: Use Them or Lose Them.
我俩纯粹是工作上的关系
Maggie, that was strictly a professional relationship.
那我和弗瑞德呢？
What do you think this is?
这个不是问句吧？
Was that a rhetorical question?
独守空闺的滋味确实不好受
Waiting for someone else to come home all the time is hard, Jason.
但你会习来惯过来的
But you get better at it.
但愿、如此
I hope so.
突然感到自己很傻
Suddenly I feel very silly.
也不至于用“傻”这个字
Well, "silly" is a strong word.
不过不见得不贴切
Not entirely inappropriate, but strong.
杰森，我爱你 我不会欺骗你
Jason, I love you. I could never cheat on you.
是吗？
Yeah?
是的
Yeah.
-谢谢你 -不客气
- Well, thank you. - Well, you're welcome.
毛毛虫!
Caterpillars!
-什么？ -本应该研究毛毛虫
- What? - it's obvious. Ben should do caterpillars.
-好主意 -谢谢
- Now that's a great idea. - Thanks.
今晚并没有白来
it's a good thing I came down here tonight.
本的毛虫研究怎样了？
So, how's Ben doing with his caterpillars?
已经被别人研究过了
Somebody else was already doing caterpillars.
本要想个新课题
Ben had to think of a new project.
新课题？拜托
A new project? Please.
很好吃
Pretty good.
我的霉菌实验品呢？
Hey, where's my mold experiment?
[zeroxia@gmail.com] 2006.03.07